<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:base="https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rafa&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Rafael&#39;s reflections on life and other things.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Shame</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250923-shame/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to Oktoberfest yesterday.&lt;br&gt;
I was actually looking forward to it, to blow off some steam and forget about my worries for at least a few minutes. I did not go for the last 2 years, and the memories I had from before that were that it was a stinky place full of tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a table reservation this time, so the environment was nice this time. My friends are great, and the conversation was chill. Even the food was surprisingly good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I drank way too much. To the point where I was falling around and embarrassing myself.&lt;br&gt;
An Australian bloke who could barely stay on his feet himself threatened that he would kill me because he thought I was chatting up his girlfriend. I lost a 50€ bill somewhere, and after waiting for some Flammkuchen I cannot remember a single thing anymore. I just remember miraculously opening the door to my place, stumbling into the kitchen to drink some water, shattering a plate on the floor, cutting myself on my little toe, bleeding everywhere, and then falling into bed and basically passing out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up religiously at 8 this morning when the alarm rang to head to the office for work, but I still felt drunk and sick until noon. I did not tidy the shattered plate until a few minutes ago. Some blood splatters are still here and there, on some furniture and the laminate. The whole day has been like a trance. What the fuck am I doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fun, but currently, I only feel shame. I feel guilty, dirty, and irresponsible.&lt;br&gt;
I will go to Oktoberfest again, but the moral is that I have to be an adult. I knew my limits, and I chose to ignore them. This is not about being risk-averse; I acted like an idiot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250923-shame/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constants</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250920-constants/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is funny how things change constantly. Like, everything, drastically, very fast.&lt;br&gt;
As someone who is calm and reflected, I would just wish sometimes that things could just stay the same. If it is good, why change? As it turns out, humans and life itself are quite complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think my cravings for stability will ever be satisfied.&lt;br&gt;
You can even argue that the constant change is what &lt;a href=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250224-wonder/&quot;&gt;makes life beautiful&lt;/a&gt;. Worth living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was walking up with a colleague and friend to &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/WYQuEzUBYv7jQEEz8&quot;&gt;Havana Club&lt;/a&gt;, a lovely bar in Munich with the best daiquiris I have ever had in my life, I noticed that almost every single time I had been there, one particular blond waiter had always attended me.&lt;br&gt;
Always friendly, polite, and helpful. Through breakups, sorrow, stress, but also wonderful and magical beginnings.&lt;br&gt;
And funnily enough, he was there, albeit with a shorter haircut. I asked him how long he had been working there, and he replied 6 years (I have been in Munich for 5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weird thought popped into my head that, during my time in Munich, this waiter had been the only real constant in my life.&lt;br&gt;
Friend groups, hobbies, partners, flats, dreams, and aspirations. They all changed. Aside from my employer, everything has been constantly shifting. But that cocktail bar has been a refuge and haven for me in good and bad times. There, I cried and I laughed and flirted and was supportive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more constants, of course. My family, and some long-term friends that I am still in contact with. And nobody is to say that a recent variable cannot become a constant for the rest of your life.&lt;br&gt;
In a world in which everything is fleeting and fragile, is it up to us to take care of the things we value and want to preserve. It takes time and energy, and more often than not it feels easier to just ignore the bridge and let it burn down.&lt;br&gt;
New things are exciting - and I hope to experience so many more of them! But it is mystical and reassuring that there are some people who stand the test of time, unwavering, that you can come back to and call home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250920-constants/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Deserve Better</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250915-you-deserve-better/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You deserve someone that wants to be with you.&lt;br&gt;
You deserve someone that does not need convincing of you worth.&lt;br&gt;
You deserve someone emotionally mature and stable, that communicates their feelings clearly and openly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, you are consumed by the emotions: the pain, the disappointment, and the betrayal.&lt;br&gt;
But you will focus on the facts. You dodged a bullet.&lt;br&gt;
This would have happened sooner or later, and it is good it happened now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t need them. They need you. You are fine without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You gave everything, it will never be enough for the wrong person.&lt;br&gt;
For the right person, you will be enough even on your worst days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will not give yourself up and put your mental stability on the line for someone that is not willing to do the same for you. You deserve someone that decides even in uncertain times that the relationship is more important than the discomfort. That shows up even if it is not their current first priority, and invests energy in you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You gave up many things because you thought the next step would be a life together.&lt;br&gt;
But you have time, and there is so much yet to see.&lt;br&gt;
You will focus on what brings you joy. Meeting your friends and family, and others that truly care about you.&lt;br&gt;
Attend random events, and do the things that you have always wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You deserve better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250915-you-deserve-better/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Risk-Taking</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250813-on-risk-taking/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My brother and I were talking just a few minutes before going out to the water to windsurf what equipment we were going to use. We are not pros, not even close. In fact, we are still making attempts to reduce the volume of our boards below 120 liters.&lt;br&gt;
And I was feeling spicy today: I would try out the 112L board they had for rent!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hard. The board was more unstable than the larger ones, the wind was gusty, and the water was quite choppy. But it went well - until it didn&#39;t. I went out quite far during the last round and fell harness-hook-first on the mast. The 90% carbon fibre mast immediately broke in half with a crack. The sail floated limply in the water.&lt;br&gt;
...Bad bad bad...!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there I was, 1.5km away from the beach, with 2-meter waves, and no way to sail back.&lt;br&gt;
I hoped for a rescue, but for some reason, I thought I remembered that this spot had none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started swimming, and it went quite well. Ignoring the instinct to panic, that is, because it is really hard to tell how fast you are advancing and how much water is still left between you and the beach, or if you are hopelessly drifting with the waves and the current. But you just have to keep swimming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I met my brother along the way and somehow managed to gesture and shout that my mast was broken. He sailed back, and before I knew it, a jet ski of the Red Cross was picking me up. Phew.&lt;br&gt;
That saved me a whole lot of swimming. Thanks, bro!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all ended well, but these things always eat at me from the inside out. It is a blend of shock, shame, inadequacy, remorse, and frustration. Comments always range from &amp;quot;Man, it happens&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;Expensive hobby, huh?&amp;quot; and even the occasional &amp;quot;Thanks for regularly breaking equipment, Rafa!&amp;quot; 🫤 Not a great feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am convinced the fastest way to progress is to take a risk and &amp;quot;just do it&amp;quot;. Many times, the only thing holding us back is ourselves, and if you never try, you will never know. Why did it feel so awful, though? It was hard, so hard, to just say &amp;quot;It does indeed just happen, and I am going to try again tomorrow!&amp;quot;. After all, there are consequences and real dangers: broken bones, costly equipment, or your reputation.&lt;br&gt;
Therefore, I have always been on the cautious side of things. It is better to prevent than to mend, right? Always ask for permission, then you won&#39;t have to ask for forgiveness.&lt;br&gt;
However, I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to learn, and I want to make the mistakes that will happen sooner or later and see some progress. To come out of the water and say: &amp;quot;Hell yeah, I tried and it was hard, but I made it work&amp;quot;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think with a few tweaks, the weird feeling of failure could have been transformed into something more constructive. Some genuinely encouraging words, no sassy jokes, some well-meant advice, and hints on what to watch out for. A nudge to just go for it again the next time, and an acknowledgement for taking the risk and at least trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I guess in the same way that one cannot expect the person taking the risk to just &lt;em&gt;suck it up&lt;/em&gt; when it does not work out (because the feeling of failure is so hard-wired), one can not expect for the people surrounding them to be genuine and encouraging, because we only really have control over our own actions, and not the ones of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My learnings are twofold.&lt;br&gt;
First, I want to be a person who is less deterred by failure, recognizing that some real, permanent growth is happening. I will be courageous and bold before trying something new, when the little internal voice is telling me to stop because &amp;quot;everything will surely go horribly wrong and everyone is going to die&amp;quot;. The potential rewards outweigh the drawbacks. Also, the little voice has no idea what it is talking about.&lt;br&gt;
Second, I want to be a person who encourages others to take calculated risks, under the assumption that it is the fastest and best way to learn. I will recognize that occasional failures do happen and support anyone to give it another go with genuine appreciation and respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can all be better, together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250813-on-risk-taking/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Diving and Mind Tricks</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250727-on-diving-and-mind-tricks/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I had my first SCUBA diving experience - and it was incredible!&lt;br&gt;
In the days leading up to it, I felt quite nervous. It was something completely new after all, and from what I have heard, it can be quite dangerous if proper precautions are not taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an introduction from the extremely competent, thorough, and friendly instructors, we strapped on the (heavy!) equipment and plunged into the water. And this is when it started:&lt;br&gt;
Close to the beach, we had to kneel down on the seabed and go through the basic skills. Emptying the goggles of water by pushing it out with air from our noses, equalizing the pressure in the ears, etc. While it is already weird to have a blocked nose and breathe only through your mouth, the thing that annoyed me most was the constant waves (I know, right hahaha).&lt;br&gt;
With each wave, I felt clumsier. They would flip me on my back, carry me into rocks, get my fins tangled up, and seem to make staying still on the seabed and following the instructors&#39; prompts completely impossible. With each wave, I was feeling more nervous and insecure. If this was the easy part, what was still ahead of me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggled for approximately ten minutes, which felt like an eternity. The goggles were pressing on my nose uncomfortably, and I had the constant worry that the instructors were going to abort at any moment.&lt;br&gt;
And then something clicked. I either got used to it or I started actually thinking with my brain.&lt;br&gt;
I took a wider stance with my knees and tried to predict the waves to balance preemptively. I calmed down, slowed my breath, and tried to become one with the surroundings.&lt;br&gt;
And everything was immediately better in a matter of seconds. And from there, everything else &lt;em&gt;just worked&lt;/em&gt;™.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We swam out, even reached a depth of 10 meters, saw a ton of fish (sadly no turtles), and it was a blast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And suddenly it hit again. Am I not getting enough air? Why is the air I am exhaling sounding louder than previously when rising to the surface past my ears? Am I tiring myself too much while swimming - will my legs cramp up soon? And I swear in this moment, I felt I was not getting enough air. Funny thing is: I totally &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; getting enough air! It was all actually &lt;em&gt;completely fine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
I was telling myself that something was wrong, and it immediately felt like something was actually wrong. It was as if something inside of me was still trying to resist and tell me I am going to die there, that I was not prepared, and would make a horrible mistake. And just as fast as the feeling came, it went again. I calmed myself down, and everything was ok. What the hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brain plays tricks on you. And in the stress and the hectic, it is easy to fall into a negative cycle of doom and gloom. Everything seems bad as soon as you think it is bad, and in the moment, it all feels too real, and the fear and the stress are palpable and scary.&lt;br&gt;
But as fast as it all comes, it all goes. A deep breath, a nudge to relax and look at things clearly. To notice that we are alive and still breathing, privileged, and incredibly lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250727-on-diving-and-mind-tricks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ginger Bug Experiments</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250707-ginger-bug-experiments/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always wanted to make my own Kombucha.&lt;br&gt;
The major hurdle however was that you need a SCOBY to get started, which you can either get from someone who donates a piece of theirs or by buying it somewhere (e.g. on the internet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my friend made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://danbos.de/posts/making-ginger-bug&quot;&gt;post about his Ginger Bug&lt;/a&gt;, I got quite excited!&lt;br&gt;
The main difference to a SCOBY is that the wild yeast doing the fermentation is already readily available on the skin of conventional over-the-counter organic ginger from your local grocery store!&lt;br&gt;
So I decided to give it a try and... failed. My friend reported the same outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I decided to document some highlights of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, I just glanced over the instructions and bought the necessary ingredients. How hard could it be. Something that immediately throws me off is the American way of measuring everything in (standardized!) cups, tablespoons, and so on, down to 1/8th of a teaspoon!?&lt;br&gt;
Over the years I have repeatedly tried to follow American recipes and using online conversion tools because obviously, a volumetric cup of water is not the same weight as a cup of flour or sugar or even butter.&lt;br&gt;
Maybe I am also just dumb? In any case, it never works out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, after setting up the starter, this is how it looked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/media/ginger_bug.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Ginger Bug Starter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The freshly set up and fed Ginger Bug&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After feeding it a teaspoon of ginger and a teaspoon of sugar every day, everything started looking as it should around day 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/media/ginger_bug2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Ginger Bug Starter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Evolving Ginger Bug, slightly foamy now&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I repeated until day 5 or so and then put it in the fridge as vaguely indicated in the recipe.&lt;br&gt;
This would allow me to just feed it once a week because the yeast would go partially dormant at low temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now about the exciting part! &lt;em&gt;The ginger beer!&lt;/em&gt; I bought the swing top bottles and followed the instructions precisely.&lt;br&gt;
And I have to say it did not look bad at this point!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/media/ginger_beer.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Ginger Beer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Freshly prepared Ginger Beer&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then everything basically stopped... No pressure building up, no signs of life apart from excruciatingly slowly building up sediment (which is supposed to be a good sign) and a few very small bubbles on the bottle walls.&lt;br&gt;
No satisfying popping when &amp;quot;burping&amp;quot; the sodas. Just confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I waited for more than 5 days, but frustration caught up and I tipped it down the kitchen sink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I do something wrong? Probably.&lt;br&gt;
I even asked ChatGPT what the issue could have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is my diagnosis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too little food when preparing the Ginger Bug starter:&lt;br&gt;
I fed it one teaspoon ginger and sugar respectively daily, but it should have been a tablespoon. It is possible the yeast did not have enough sustenance available to form a strong culture in the limited time span I gave it outside of the fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slightly off measurements?&lt;br&gt;
I used European tea- and tablespoons and when a cup was needed I used an English teacup, which is possibly too small.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The yeast was dormant when in the fridge and I used the starter directly to prepare the soda.&lt;br&gt;
The recommendation online seems to be to leave it outside for a few hours during the weekly feeding, and generally &amp;quot;waking it up&amp;quot; before preparing soda.&lt;br&gt;
I guess the yeast count was just too small and it did not ramp up fast enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used water from the sink and not mineral bottled water.&lt;br&gt;
While I think it should be fine, something in the water here could have halted the development of the yeast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other contaminants&lt;br&gt;
I did not go through the effort of sterilizing all bottles and utensils.&lt;br&gt;
While mold never formed visibly, who knows what other life forms the yeast had to compete with in this primordial soup?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would have been a possibility to try reviving the Ginger Bug, but I decided to start from zero.&lt;br&gt;
I have now bought American standardized measuring cups and spoons and have set up a new Ginger Bug starter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will post an update if this one goes well! Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250707-ginger-bug-experiments/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer and Gardening</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250703-summer-and-gardening/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I was looking forward to when moving to the new flat was the larger balcony and the connected possibilities.&lt;br&gt;
While it is too narrow to properly sit and spend the whole day there, it is perfect for hanging some clothes out to dry or for a little hobby gardening!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how it is looking from the back garden area (since it lies on the opposite side of the street):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/media/flowers1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Balcony&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View of passers-by of the balcony.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/media/flowers2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Flowers Close-up&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/media/flowers3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Flowers Close-up&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought the flowers in pots and simply moved them to the flower boxes. They have grown beautifully and require little to no maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend would have preferred to grow all plants from seeds.&lt;br&gt;
While I agree that is would have been much nicer, my previous experience has also been that there a many more things to watch out for.&lt;br&gt;
Mainly, the saplings need a warm temperature initially, and keeping them inside of the flat mostly just led to fungus gnats.&lt;br&gt;
Maybe I am just bad a watering them properly. In any case, it is just a lot more work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I agreed to give some mini-tomatoes a try!&lt;br&gt;
They are looking good and healthy and are now positioned on the balcony, too.&lt;br&gt;
I am not sure how long it will take for them to grow some actual tomatoes, but I hope it happens before summer is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/media/tomatoes.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Tomatoes&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Tomatoes on the balcony.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250703-summer-and-gardening/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chains of the Crown</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250611-chains-of-the-crown/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been pretty caught up the past few days with a small GameDev project of mine. The name I have decided to give it for now is &lt;em&gt;Chains of the Crown&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I dream of having some sort of artistic talent sometimes, I have to admit that asset creation was never my strong suit. I dabbled here and there for some years creating my own clunky-looking Blender robots back when I was 15, but that is pretty much as far as I got.&lt;br&gt;
Luckily, kind-hearted people on the Internet exist, and publish their work for free!&lt;br&gt;
Scrolling through &lt;a href=&quot;http://itch.io&quot;&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt;, I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrabling.itch.io/pixel-isometric-tiles&quot;&gt;a beautiful isometric tileset&lt;/a&gt;. A few more minutes of research and more pixel art assets popped up. In this case,&lt;a href=&quot;https://lyaseek.itch.io/minifhumans&quot;&gt; some cute medieval characters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have long been a huge fan of the XCOM franchise. Could I ever hope to create something like this? In any case, even if I don&#39;t finish, what is the harm in starting and learning something along the way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is the current, still very raw state! &lt;em&gt;Chains of the Crown&lt;/em&gt; is a turn-based tactical combat game, in which your character, a knight fallen from the grace of the King, joins the farmers to overthrow their repressing ruler. One thing I am especially proud of is the conservation of the axis-aligned pixel art! You see, I wanted the game to look like the screenshots of the isometric tileset I found, which includes tiles at different elevations.&lt;br&gt;
At first, I went the 2D route and used the tileset as it was intended: on a plane that only simulates depth. But placing a unit behind any elevation instantly led to a bad UX. How could you tell where your units were, at what depth, and what other places they could reach if you could not see anything behind a sufficiently high hill?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some brainstorming, I found the solution!&lt;br&gt;
The 2D tiles are placed on 3D positions, but &amp;quot;billboard&amp;quot; to always face the camera. With smart placement of the orthogonal camera, the scene looks flat and the pixels are still axis-aligned, without any gaps between them! 🥳 This approach allows pivoting the camera to face the scene from one of four possible angles at which the effect is preserved. While the tiles glitch into each other on rotation, in my opinion, the fast camera movement creates a believable effect that even has its very own unique(?) charm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a GIF to show the current progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/media/chains_of_the_crown.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Chains of the Crown Work-In-Progress&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Demonstration of the camera rotation feature, with some unit selection and movement.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250611-chains-of-the-crown/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just Ship It</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250511-just-ship-it/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have many hobby projects. In fact, every time I am working on one it becomes a bit tedious, I have an incredibly exciting different and new idea, and start working on the new one.&lt;br&gt;
This is cool - hobby projects are not work. In fact, they should not at all be about &lt;em&gt;getting things done&lt;/em&gt;, nobody is paying you for this and there will be no consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the flip side is that projects disappear at the bottom of a deep (digital) crate and never see the light of day. After years of oblivion, you might randomly find them again, will be ashamed they ever existed, and simply delete them unceremoniously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why though? How can this be &amp;quot;better&amp;quot; than, even if the project is not polished and ready for the world, just putting the idea out there? Let me introduce you to the (incredibly radical, I know) idea of: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Just ship it!&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;em&gt;shipping it&lt;/em&gt; I don&#39;t mean setting up a Kubernetes cluster, making your app redundant across multiple countries and test-pyramiding the hell out of it so that it never ever fails (the kind of thing you do at your paid daily job). What I mean with this is: just make it available in some way on the Internet, so that someone &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of a GitHub repo, write a short README and make it public. If it is a website, build it statically and host it for free on GitHub Pages or Vercel or your provider of choice. For a CLI tool, document it just enough for people to run the most basic use case, then upload it somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bet you are already feeling the internal resistance. Why is this so hard? I believe the main factor that holds you back is &lt;em&gt;shame&lt;/em&gt;. As professionals, should we not be able to build software in a professional way? Clean code, clean architecture, no bugs, perfect documentation, etc etc. I mean, what if someone saw this unfinished POC and thought: &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Damn dude, what an absolute amateur...&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, what I have come to believe is: nobody really cares that much. In fact, if the idea is even remotely interesting to someone stumbling over it, they will appreciate it rather than get lost in the implementation details!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you some more reasons why there are more advantages to &lt;em&gt;just shipping it&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will feel proud! And you should! You put time and effort into something and you got it out there! Way to go!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just ship it&lt;/em&gt; attitude will force you to focus on the most relevant, essential parts of your idea (it would embarrassing if they are missing, right?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once published, you will have additional drive to iterate on the current state and improve it. This motivation to iron it out would just not be there if the project was wasting away on your hard drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone genuinely interested might find it and be entertained and inspired!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone might find it actually useful and ask for more features, which in turn means more motivation to work on it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone might give you constructive feedback (in the form of a pull request, comment, or other). And: should you currently have no time or motivation, you can always choose to ignore it - there is literally no real pressure to immediately react.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to address the main fear of shame: nobody has ever written to me expressing their disgust at any published project. When you find something on the Internet that you don&#39;t find mind-blowing, you simply move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a very specific example, see Minecraft! You can browse the Internet and easily find out that the creator, Markus Persson (&lt;em&gt;Notch&lt;/em&gt;), is not considered to be a good programmer by the community. When Mojang employed additional programmers, the game needed a complete rewrite! So what? Minecraft had and still has a huge fanbase, even before it was sold to Microsoft for a unfathomable amounts of money! What would have happened if Notch was ashamed of his code quality an programming skills? Or could not get over &amp;quot;that one small bug that happens when you place a certain block type on top of another one&amp;quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a call to action: what project is dusting in your digital crate? What is the smallest delta you need to tackle to make this your &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;minimum not-shameful product&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;br&gt;
Then go and do exactly that and get it out there! Then let me know how it went!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250511-just-ship-it/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F*ck your Why</title>
      <link>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250330-fck-your-why/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find it crazy how everything we do nowadays has to have an ulterior motive. Even your hobby projects are supposed to be a form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.solipsys.co.uk/new/SellYourselfSellYourWork.html&quot;&gt;advertisement for yourself, your reputation, and your career&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It always has to be &lt;em&gt;something you can write on your CV afterward&lt;/em&gt;. Did you struggle, did you hate every second of it? Well, it does not matter, it is an investment in yourself, right? In fact, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;the hustle is what makes you stronger, bro&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
You struggle through it and then you reap the delayed gratification later in the form of respect, money, and admiration as Elon Musk&#39;s hardest-working employee. Obviously, like any self-respecting grown-up you do everything for a reason. You have a purpose, a &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a work context starting with your why might make sense. Your employer wants to know why he is paying you. After work, this is the single most destructive thought you can have.&lt;br&gt;
Imagine you really feel like spending some time planting some herbs on your balcony. But the overthinking starts: how can I promote this once it is done? Maybe an automated smart herb planter on Kickstarter? Is this interesting to the FANG recruiters that might find it?&lt;br&gt;
Is this game dev project I am excited about a waste of time - should I instead be reading up on the latest GenAI buzz?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about you chill for a second. Yeah, just chill. How about your &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; being &lt;em&gt;because I feel like it&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;because it is fun&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you doing all these things for yourself? Or are you doing them because someone told you that &lt;em&gt;it is what you should be doing right now&lt;/em&gt;? For &amp;quot;the people that care about you&amp;quot;, but are more excited about their Bitcoin investment than about your life?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;You should be reading up on ETFs. You should be getting that AWS certification on your weekends.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; Give me a break and let me knit my socks in peace.&lt;br&gt;
I don&#39;t want to accept I cannot enjoy myself spending 3 hours in the kitchen cooking something I really look forward to trying, because it is a &amp;quot;waste of time&amp;quot;. Instead, I apparently should be getting unhealthy crap food delivered while I write an email to my manager informing them of the great progress I made during the weekend by turning the client&#39;s success my personal quest and working unpaid overtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very privileged view. It assumes you have a stable job and you are not getting 100% of your gratification and purpose from it. It assumes you have hobbies and passions and the feeling you never have any time for them because &amp;quot;more productive tasks&amp;quot; always overshadow them. If you feel you are unhappy with what you have, by all means, put all the energy and effort you can muster into changing it to something better.&lt;br&gt;
A balanced and rested mind is more effective than an overworked one. Take time for yourself and your mental well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rafael Kübler da Silva</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://rafaelkuebler.github.io/posts/20250330-fck-your-why/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>